DYLAN PAVELKO

Product Leader

dpavelko@gmail.com Los Angeles, CA

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE DEGREE IN ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING

California Polytechnic State University, San Luis Obispo

EXPERTISE

Product Management Leading Teams Product Strategy Data-Driven Customer Relationships

EXPANDED & INTERACTIVE

dylanpavelko.com/CV

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Dylan Pavelko has more than a decade of product leadership experience with emerging software products. He helped Workday grow from a pre-IPO company of fewer than 1,000 employees generating \$274M to an 18,000+ employee, Fortune 500 company making over \$8B in annual revenue.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Manager, Product Management, Workday

2.6+ years

Manager, Product Management - Los Angeles, CA Apr 2022 - Present
Passionate about building high-performing product management teams focused
on delivering results. Leading product teams focused on delivering high-quality,
consumer-based student user experiences, and sophisticated back-office processing
for administrators to uphold institutional academic policies.

- Manage, hire, coach, and retain a team of product managers across all levels of seniority, based in offices across North America, each owning their own product portfolio and roadmap.
- Establish clear, high-value, focused objectives and key results (OKRs) to empower teams to move more autonomously towards a shared vision with
- Delivered 211 customer-facing features to production over five six-month release cycles.

Product Functional Architect, Workday

2.6 years

Principal Product Manager - Los Angeles, CA Senior Product Manager - Pleasanton, CA Jun 2021 - Apr 2022 Sept 2017 - May 2019

Nicknamed "The PM Whisperer" for my ability to successfully lead initiatives across diverse teams and ensure the scalability of Workday Student. Selected as Workday Student's first Functional Architect, where I defined the role and responsibilities for the position.

- Led functional design and coordination across 30+ scrum teams for multi-year initiatives aimed at significantly increasing product-market fit.
- Mentored other product managers on how to represent the voice of the customer while balancing technical, design, and business trade-offs.
- Served as part of the senior leadership team, regularly representing the organization externally as a subject matter expert, including in contract negotiations.
- Led discovery to identify top machine learning/AI use cases.

Product Strategy Director, Workday

2.2 years

Product Strategy Director - Los Angeles, CA

May 2019 - Jun 2021

Crafted product visions that drove value for Workday and it's customers by balancing big-picture thinking with detailed analysis. Played a key role in defining the next chapter of growth by leading initiatives to quantify and assess over \$950M in annual recurring revenue from global market opportunities.

- Partnered with product marketing, value management, and competitive intelligence teams to ensure the sales team was equipped with the right positioning to maximize subscription sales.
- Led product adoption analytics project to make data-driven decisions for over 800 features.
- Led an Australian market-fit customer discovery project for two years that included two multiday, in-person workshops. This work led to the opening of new markets for Workday.
- Represented the organization externally by leading sessions at industry analyst briefings, industry conferences, and customer executive advisory council meetings.

Senior Product Manager, Workday

4 years

Senior Product Manager - Pleasanton, CA Product Manager - Pleasanton, CA May 2016 - Sept 2017

Oct 2013 - May 2016

A founding member of the product management team responsible for creating the first cloud-based Student Information System for higher education. Workday Student operated as a B2B startup within a larger parent company, starting with zero lines of code and zero customers.

- Conducted extensive customer sessions to help inform the product vision and requirements.
- Hosted virtual and on-site user research studies to validate product risks and assumptions.
- Led all product owner related scrum activities associated with agile software development.
- Applied systems thinking to develop several adaptable platform frameworks that allowed Workday to scale to meet diverse business requirements.
- Designed and continuously iterated on consumer-based experiences, focusing on customers' needs while ensuring scalability for the product vision and larger customers.
- Represented the organization at industry events, conferences, and software partner meetings.

Test Automation Engineer, Workday

1.8 years

Test Automation Engineer - Pleasanton, CA

Mar 2013 - Oct 2013

Associate Test Automation Engineer - Pleasanton, CA

Jan 2012 - Mar 2013

Developed and maintained automated regression testing using a blend of proprietary and opensource automated testing frameworks, including Selenium and SoapUI.

- Supported transition from a waterfall to an agile development methodology.
- Awarded the inaugural company-wide "Golden Bug" quality assurance award.

Automated Test Developer, Mindbody

6 months

Automated Test Developer - San Luis Obispo, CA

Jul 2011 - Dec 2011

Developed automated system regression tests for B2B platform serving over 10,000+ customers.

Created automated system regression tests for consumer-facing storefront.